

Personal Info

Date of birth 14/3 1995
Nationality Egyptian
Marital Status Exempted
Phone (+20) 1119421377
E-mail

moh.shehata143@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/muhammadshehata-450116145

Hard Skills

ASP.net C#| & PHP

WordPress Plugin's

HTML5 & CSS3 & SASS

JS & jQuery & Bootstrap5

SQL Database & API's

Soft Skills

Problem Solving

Collaboration

Flexibility

Software

MS Visual Studio & VS Code

MS SQL Server & My SQL

DevExpress & Crystal Reports

Git & GitHub

Languages

Arabic Native Language

English good knowledge

Hobbies







I'm a Web Developer and Computer Science Researcher. I've more than 3 years of experience building web and desktop applications using ASP .NET and PHP. I've worked internationally remotely and also worked internally on projects for businesses, agencies, and start-ups.

Experience

Jan-2021 -Present

Web Developer

Expert Online Solutions, Florida New York, US.

- Worked on analyzing many projects, UI design, and database.
- Designed, Developed, and Maintenance for 3 websites and WordPress Plugins by PHP.

Oct-2018 -Present

Teaching Assistant of MIS

Higher Institute for Advanced Studies in Haram, Giza, Egypt.

- Training students on the practical and relevant contents of the Material.
- Training students to implement projects for all practical materials, and receive projects from students and discuss.
- Evaluating students, controlling the work of the year, and monitoring students in exams.

May-2018 - Oct-2019

Web Developer

S-Smart, Giza, Egypt.

- Worked on analyzing many projects and determining customer requirements.
- worked on more than 10 SQL database design projects and Improved speed to complete projects.
- Designed, Developed, and provided maintenance for 10+ websites and desktop applications by C#.
 Achieved 100% client satisfaction.

May-2017 -May-2018

Freelance Web Developer

- Communicated with customers to implement Web Services.
- Trouble-shot and fixed problems through customer requests.
- Designed and built websites and software from the start to the stage of software testing, maintenance, and after-sales services.

Certificates

- 2021 Mobile Application Development Certification, Egyptian Ministry of Communications and Information Technology.
- **2016** International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL) certification, Microsoft.
- **2014** Personal Strategic Planning Certification, IAPTLD Professional Trainer (PT).

Education

Oct 2021 - Expected 2022	Pre-Masters in Computer Science in Progress Faculty of Graduate Studies and Statistical Research, Cairo University, Egypt.
Oct 2019 - May 2021	Diploma in Computer Science Faculty of Graduate Studies and Statistical Research, Cairo University, Egypt. 3.13 GPA
May 2014 - May 2018	 Bachelor of Management Information Systems Higher Institute of Advanced Studies in Haram, Egypt. 3.54 GPA I Participated in the science club's competition for innovations and inventions (Workshops), 2018. I received a certificate for the Science Club's Competition, 2018.

Courses

Nov - Des 2020	Diploma in Mobile Application Development (Flutter) Online by The Ministry of Communications and Information Technology.
Oct 2020	Diploma in Life Skills Online by The Ministry of Communications and Information Technology.
July 2014 - Sept 2016	ICDL v5 Professional Training for ICDL Curriculum Software Development Center and Medical Engineering Consultancy. Cairo University.
Apr - Aug 2014	Diploma in Human Development Smart Center in Bani Mazar. Minya.
July - Aug 2010	Professional Training for Microsoft Office 2003 Office Application Packs Secondary School for Boys New Beni Mazar. Minya.